{
    "id": "163_Entertainment_618",
    "claim": "Leaders of other parties reject their families living outside the country; those of AMLO and Dante Delgado, with university studies, but in MexicoThe PAN national president, Ricardo Anaya Cortes, with his family in Atlanta, Georgia, United States The leaders of the country's main political forces said they do not keep their family living abroad as does the president of the National Action Party (PAN), Ricardo Anaya Cortes. After EL UNIVERSAL announced that the PAN national leader keeps his family in the United States with certain luxuries, some party leaders refused to let them do the same. Questioned about this, teams of PRI, Morena, Movimiento Ciudadano, PVEM and PRD leaders responded that their children and wives live in Mexico. In the case of Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador, president of Morena, his older children have completed their university studies; some did so at the National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM), while his younger son studies at a school in Tlalpan. In the case of Dante Delgado, national coordinator of the Citizens' Movement (MC), his childrenlike those of Lopez Obradorare adults and finished their studies several years ago. Sources consulted by this newspaper reported that the children of the leader of the orange party attended university outside Mexico City, but not in another country. In the case of Enrique Ochoa Reza, national leader of the Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI), his team reported that he has a two-year-old daughter living in Mexico. In turn, Alejandra Barrales Magdaleno, national president of the Party of the Democratic Revolution (PRD), has a little daughter who is not yet in school. Asked about this, the president of the Green Ecological Party of Mexico (PVEM), Carlos Puente, said that he has no children. The Panista's Incomes. In yesterday's edition, EL UNIVERSAL published that the leader of National Action, Ricardo Anaya, keeps his three underage children and his wife in Atlanta, Georgia, United States, because minors study English in one of the most exclusive schools in the area and their overheads are estimated at approximately million 1,000 pesos. Public documents from US authorities obtained by EL UNIVERSAL detail that the family of Anaya Cortes rents the property located in the number  of Bishop Lake Road, Atlanta, a house that has five bedrooms and access to a lake for which it pays 1,000  dollars of rent (almost 1,000 pesos per month with an exchange rate of  pesos with  cents). Anaya Cortes himself confirmed that he rents the house, but says that he spends a thousand dollars a month, equivalent to a thousand dollars a year and that for a whole year it means an expense of a thousand dollars a year. According to the Atlanta Tax Register and online valuations of U.S. real estate, the residence in which the family of the National President of the PAN lives has a value ranging from 1,000  to 1,000 $. Level school. Anaya's three children attend the High Meadows School, one of the most expensive and exclusive institutions in the area. The school is located at  in Willeo Road, Roswell, Georgia, less than  kilometers from the house rented by the Anaya family; it offers music, performing arts, visual arts and languages classes, among others. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "www.eluniversal.com.mx",
    "date": "04/11/2016",
    "veracity": 1,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "Leaders of other parties reject families living outside the country ; those of AMLO and Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador, president of Morena , his childrenlike those of Lopez Obradorare university studies, but in MexicoThe PAN national president, Ricardo Anaya Cortes the Citizens' Movement (MC) Leaders of other parties said Leaders of other parties do not keep family has abroad as does PRI MexicoThe PAN national president, Ricardo Anaya Cortes .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.eluniversal.com.mx report on 04/11/2016?",
                    "answer": "Leaders of other parties reject families living outside the country"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What countries do leaders of other parties reject families living outside of the country?",
                    "score": 0.7971,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tother|amod\tliving outside the country|acl\toutside the country|prep\tthe|det\tthe country|pobj\t;|punct\tand|cc\t,|punct\t,|punct\t,|punct\tbut|cc\tin|conj\tMexicoThe|punct\tnational|amod\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthe Citizens '|poss\t'|case\t(|punct\t)|punct\tother|amod\tother|amod\tdo|aux\tnot|neg\tas|mark\tas does PRI|advcl\tMexicoThe|punct\tnational|amod\t,|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many family members of Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador live outside the country?",
                    "score": 0.6857,
                    "answers": "Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador , president of Morena|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between AMLO and Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador?",
                    "score": 0.6139,
                    "answers": "that Leaders of other parties reject families living outside the country ; those of AMLO and Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador , president of Morena , his childrenlike those of Lopez Obradorare university studies , but in|ccomp\tAndres|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the relationship between Lopez Obrador and AMLO?",
                    "score": 0.6033,
                    "answers": "Lopez Obradorare university studies|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "After EL UNIVERSAL announced the president of the Green Ecological Party of Mexico (PVEM), Carlos Puente United States Enrique Ochoa Reza, national leader of the Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI) in PAN with certain luxuries, some party leaders refused to let them do the same.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did some party leaders do after EL UNIVERSAL announced Carlos Puente United States Enrique Ochoa Reza?",
                    "answer": "some party leaders refused to let them do the same"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the party that Carlos Puente United States Enrique Ochoa Reza was president of?",
                    "score": 0.6493,
                    "answers": "Green|compound\tparty|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the luxuries of the PVEM party?",
                    "score": 0.62,
                    "answers": "with certain luxuries|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are some of the luxuries of PVEM?",
                    "score": 0.6082,
                    "answers": "certain luxuries|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the president of the Green Ecological Party of Mexico (PVEM)?",
                    "score": 0.6038,
                    "answers": "Carlos|nmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Carlos Puente U States Enrique Ochoa Reza?",
                    "score": 0.5962,
                    "answers": "the Green Ecological Party of Mexico ( PVEM ) , Carlos Puente United States Enrique Ochoa Reza , national leader of the Institutional Revolutionary Party ( PRI ) in PAN|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Questioned about United States , keeps has that children the leader of National Action, Ricardo Anaya the country .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What country was the leader of National Action, Ricardo Anaya?",
                    "answer": "United States"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the history of the United States?",
                    "score": 0.6583,
                    "answers": "Questioned about United States|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the leader of National Action?",
                    "score": 0.6539,
                    "answers": "www.eluniversal.com.mx reported on 04/11/2016 that Questioned about United States , keeps has that children the leader of National Action , Ricardo Anaya the country|ROOT\ton 04/11/2016|prep\t04/11/2016|pobj\tthat|mark\tabout United States|prep\tUnited|compound\t,|punct\tkeeps|nsubj\tthat Questioned about United States , keeps has that children the leader of National Action , Ricardo Anaya the country|ccomp\tthat|mark\tchildren|dep\tthe|det\tthat children the leader of National Action , Ricardo Anaya the country|dobj\tof National Action|prep\tNational|compound\t,|punct\tRicardo|compound\tthe|det\tthe country|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In the case of teams of PRI, Morena, Movimiento Ciudadano, PVEM and PRD leaders the president of the Green Ecological Party of Mexico (PVEM), Carlos Puente , Morena have completed university studies; some did so at the National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM), while younger son studies at a school PRI .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is the president of the Green Ecological Party of Mexico?",
                    "answer": "Carlos Puente"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where did Carlos Puente's son attend school?",
                    "score": 0.8243,
                    "answers": "while younger son studies at a school PRI|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where did Carlos Puente attend school?",
                    "score": 0.8216,
                    "answers": "www.eluniversal.com.mx reported on 04/11/2016 that In the case of teams of PRI , Morena , Movimiento Ciudadano , PVEM and PRD leaders the president of the Green Ecological Party of Mexico ( PVEM ) , Carlos Puente , Morena have completed university studies ; some did so at the National Autonomous University of Mexico ( UNAM ) , while younger son studies at a school PRI|ROOT\tuniversity|compound\tat a school PRI|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What school does Carlos Puente attend?",
                    "score": 0.8167,
                    "answers": "a school PRI|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many students at UNAM have completed university studies?",
                    "score": 0.7289,
                    "answers": "that In the case of teams of PRI , Morena , Movimiento Ciudadano , PVEM and PRD leaders the president of the Green Ecological Party of Mexico ( PVEM ) , Carlos Puente , Morena have completed university studies ; some did so at the National Autonomous University of Mexico ( UNAM ) , while younger son studies at a school PRI|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the graduation rate of the teams of PRI, Morena, and Movimiento Ciudadano?",
                    "score": 0.6564,
                    "answers": "younger|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "PRI case of Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador, president of Morena minors Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador, president of Morena PRI Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador, president of Morena , his older children adults and finished studies several years ago.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador?",
                    "answer": "president of Morena"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador do with his children?",
                    "score": 0.8679,
                    "answers": "adults and finished studies several years ago|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old is Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador?",
                    "score": 0.8334,
                    "answers": "older|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Sources consulted by this newspaper reported that the children of Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador, president of Morena attended university minors .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who attended a university as a minor?",
                    "answer": "the children of Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador, president of Morena"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where did Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador attend university?",
                    "score": 0.8832,
                    "answers": "www.eluniversal.com.mx|nsubj\ton 04/11/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tthis|det\tthat|mark\tthe|det\t,|punct\tof Morena|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who were the children of Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador?",
                    "score": 0.8395,
                    "answers": "Manuel|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "minors Dante Delgado , team reported that Dante Delgado has a two-year-old daughter living in the country .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who has a two-year-old daughter living in the country?",
                    "answer": "Dante Delgado"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Is Dante Delgado's daughter living in the country?",
                    "score": 0.883,
                    "answers": "in the country|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old is Dante Delgado's daughter?",
                    "score": 0.8501,
                    "answers": "two - year - old|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where is Dante Delgado's daughter living?",
                    "score": 0.8346,
                    "answers": "the country|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where is Dante Delgado living?",
                    "score": 0.8163,
                    "answers": "living in the country|acl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Dante Delgado's father?",
                    "score": 0.762,
                    "answers": "minors Dante Delgado , team|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In turn, Alejandra Barrales Magdaleno, national president of the Party of the Democratic Revolution (PRD), has a little daughter who is not yet in school.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the PRD?",
                    "answer": "Party of the Democratic Revolution"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of Magdaleno's little daughter?",
                    "score": 0.7254,
                    "answers": "that In turn , Alejandra Barrales Magdaleno , national president of the Party of the Democratic Revolution ( PRD ) , has a little daughter who is not yet in school|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the current national president of the Party of the Democratic Revolution (PRD)?",
                    "score": 0.6953,
                    "answers": "of the Party of the Democratic Revolution ( PRD )|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Asked about this, the president of the Green Ecological Party of Mexico (PVEM), Carlos Puente, said that he has no children.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the president of the Green Ecological Party of Mexico say about Carlos Puente?",
                    "answer": "he has no children"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many children does Carlos Puente have?",
                    "score": 0.8608,
                    "answers": "www.eluniversal.com.mx|nsubj\twww.eluniversal.com.mx reported on 04/11/2016 that Asked about this , the president of the Green Ecological Party of Mexico ( PVEM ) , Carlos Puente , said that he has no children|ROOT\tthat Asked about this , the president of the Green Ecological Party of Mexico ( PVEM ) , Carlos Puente , said that he has no children|ccomp\tthat he has no children|ccomp\tno|det\tno children|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does PVEM stand for?",
                    "score": 0.7763,
                    "answers": "the Green Ecological Party of Mexico ( PVEM )|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Puente's children?",
                    "score": 0.7634,
                    "answers": "Green|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Carlos Puente and the Green Ecological Party of Mexico?",
                    "score": 0.7347,
                    "answers": "on 04/11/2016|prep\tof the Green Ecological Party of Mexico ( PVEM )|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is PVEM?",
                    "score": 0.7022,
                    "answers": "Ecological|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In yesterday's edition, EL UNIVERSAL published that the leader of National Action, Ricardo Anaya, keeps his three underage children and his wife in Atlanta, Georgia, United States, because minors study English in one of the most exclusive schools in the area and their overheads are estimated at approximately million 1,000 pesos.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Where do minors study English?",
                    "answer": "one of the most exclusive schools in the area"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many students study English in Georgia?",
                    "score": 0.664,
                    "answers": "because minors study English in one of the most exclusive schools in the area and their overheads are estimated at approximately million 1,000 pesos|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many underage children does the leader of National Action have?",
                    "score": 0.6399,
                    "answers": "www.eluniversal.com.mx reported on 04/11/2016 that In yesterday 's edition , EL UNIVERSAL published that the leader of National Action , Ricardo Anaya , keeps his three underage children and his wife in Atlanta , Georgia , United States , because minors study English in one of the most exclusive schools in the area and their overheads are estimated at approximately million 1,000 pesos|ROOT\ton 04/11/2016|prep\tthat In yesterday 's edition , EL UNIVERSAL published that the leader of National Action , Ricardo Anaya , keeps his three underage children and his wife in Atlanta , Georgia , United States , because minors study English in one of the most exclusive schools in the area and their overheads are estimated at approximately million 1,000 pesos|ccomp\tthe|det\tunderage|amod\this three underage children and his wife|dobj\tand|cc\tAtlanta , Georgia , United States|pobj\tthe|det\tmost|advmod\tin the area|prep\tthe|det\tand|cc\tare|auxpass"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Ricardo Anaya and his wife?",
                    "score": 0.5243,
                    "answers": "his wife|conj\tin Atlanta , Georgia , United States|prep\tminors|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Public documents from US authorities obtained by EL UNIVERSAL detail that the family of Anaya Cortes rents the property located in the number  of Bishop Lake Road, Atlanta, a house that has five bedrooms and access to a lake for which it pays 1,000  dollars of rent (almost 1,000 pesos per month with an exchange rate of  pesos with  cents).",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What documents were obtained by EL UNIVERSAL?",
                    "score": 0.7829,
                    "answers": "Public documents from US authorities obtained by EL UNIVERSAL|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How much money does it cost to rent the property?",
                    "score": 0.7733,
                    "answers": "access to a lake it pays for which 1,000|conj\ta lake it pays for which 1,000|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where is the property of Anaya Cortes located?",
                    "score": 0.6789,
                    "answers": "www.eluniversal.com.mx|nsubj\twww.eluniversal.com.mx reported on 04/11/2016 that Public documents from US authorities obtained by EL UNIVERSAL detail that the family of Anaya Cortes rents the property located in the number   of Bishop Lake Road , Atlanta , a house that has five bedrooms and access to a lake it pays for which 1,000   dollars of rent ( almost 1,000 pesos per month with an exchange rate of   pesos with   cents )|ROOT\ton 04/11/2016|prep\t04/11/2016|pobj\tthat|mark\tEL|compound\tthat Public documents from US authorities obtained by EL UNIVERSAL detail that the family of Anaya Cortes rents the property located in the number|ccomp\tthat|mark\tthe|det\tthat the family of Anaya Cortes rents the property located in the number|ccomp\tthe|det\tthe property located in the number|dobj\tlocated in the number|acl\tin the number|prep\tthe|det\tthe number|pobj\tof Bishop Lake Road , Atlanta , a house that has five bedrooms and access to a lake it pays for which 1,000|prep\tBishop|compound\tBishop Lake|compound\t,|punct\t,|punct\ta|det\tthat|nsubj\tand|cc\ta|det\tfor which|prep\twhich|pobj\tit|nsubj\t(|punct\talmost|advmod\tan|det\tof|prep\twith|prep\t)|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the property that the family of Anaya Cortes owns?",
                    "score": 0.6296,
                    "answers": "  of Bishop Lake Road , Atlanta , a house that has five bedrooms and access to a lake it pays for which 1,000|dep\tBishop Lake Road , Atlanta , a house that has five bedrooms and access to a lake it pays for which 1,000|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the exchange rate of the property?",
                    "score": 0.5953,
                    "answers": "exchange|compound\tan exchange rate of|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Anaya Cortes himself confirmed that he rents the house, but says that he spends a thousand dollars a month, equivalent to a thousand dollars a year and that for a whole year it means an expense of a thousand dollars a year.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who confirmed that he rents the house?",
                    "answer": "Anaya Cortes"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How much does Anaya Cortes spend on rent?",
                    "score": 0.837,
                    "answers": "says that he spends a thousand dollars a month , equivalent to a thousand dollars a year and that for a whole year it means an expense of a thousand dollars a year|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How much does it cost to rent a house?",
                    "score": 0.8362,
                    "answers": "it|nsubj\tthat for a whole year it means an expense of a thousand dollars a year|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "According to the Atlanta Tax Register and online valuations of U.S. real estate, the residence in which the family of the National President of the PAN lives has a value ranging from 1,000  to 1,000 $.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where does the family of the National President of the PAN live?",
                    "score": 0.7917,
                    "answers": "in which the family of the National President of the PAN lives|relcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Level school.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the school that was reported on 04/11/2016 by www.eluniversal.com.mx?",
                    "answer": "Level school"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the link between Level Universal and Level school?",
                    "score": 0.7621,
                    "answers": "www.eluniversal.com.mx|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Level school?",
                    "score": 0.7272,
                    "answers": "www.eluniversal.com.mx reported on 04/11/2016 that Level school|ROOT\ton 04/11/2016|prep\t04/11/2016|pobj\tthat|mark\tLevel|compound\tthat Level school|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Anaya's three children attend the High Meadows School, one of the most expensive and exclusive institutions in the area.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many of Anaya's children attend High Meadows School?",
                    "answer": "three"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many children does Anaya have?",
                    "score": 0.8636,
                    "answers": "Anaya 's three children|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many children attend High Meadows School?",
                    "score": 0.8335,
                    "answers": "High Meadows|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The school is located at  in Willeo Road, Roswell, Georgia, less than  kilometers from the house rented by the Anaya family; it offers music, performing arts, visual arts and languages classes, among others.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where is the school located?",
                    "score": 0.72,
                    "answers": "www.eluniversal.com.mx|nsubj\twww.eluniversal.com.mx reported on 04/11/2016 that The school is located at   in Willeo Road , Roswell , Georgia , less than   kilometers from the house rented by the Anaya family ; it offers music , performing arts , visual arts and languages classes , among others|ROOT\ton 04/11/2016|prep\t04/11/2016|pobj\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tThe school|nsubjpass\tis|auxpass\tThe school is located at|ccomp\tat|prep\tthat The school is located at   in Willeo Road , Roswell , Georgia , less than|dep\tin Willeo Road , Roswell , Georgia , less than|prep\tWilleo|compound\tWilleo Road , Roswell , Georgia , less than|pobj\t,|punct\tRoswell , Georgia|npadvmod\t,|punct\t,|punct\tless|amod\tless than|prep\tthe|det\tthe|det\t;|punct\tit|nsubj\t  kilometers from the house rented by the Anaya family ; it offers music , performing arts , visual arts and languages classes , among others|ccomp\tmusic , performing arts , visual arts and languages|nmod\t,|punct\tperforming|compound\tperforming arts , visual arts and languages|conj\t,|punct\tvisual|amod\tvisual arts and languages|conj\tand|cc\tlanguages|conj\tmusic , performing arts , visual arts and languages classes , among others|dobj\t,|punct\tamong others|prep\tothers|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where is the Anaya family home located?",
                    "score": 0.7165,
                    "answers": "the Anaya family|pobj"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}